# Tatyana Murashchenko

Entrepreneur, HR consultant, Soft-skills coach

tatyana.murashchenko@gmail.com

# Summary

Entrepreneur, business -trainer, coach with more than 10 years of professional experience in trainings, coaching and HR consulting. Has 8+ years of work in IT area. Main specialty: people management, soft-skills development trainings for IT professionals and business coaching in IT. Has worked with EU and US customers to create the affiliates in Ukraine from scratch including creation and implementation of HR policy. Has strong communicative and problem solving skills.

Always glad to new connections!

# Experience

### COO/HR consultant at Code Melon sp. z o.o.

November 2014 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Code Melon is a modern IT company specialized on enterprise development provided with a highly skilled team of experienced experts. We always ready to take the tasks of any level of complexity. Clear vision of europian business structure allows us to work with any type of customers from small companies and individuals to the largest ones. Our main office headquarted in Poland (Cracow) and it has huge support from other branches from Ukraine. Code Melon has wide knowledge and strong experience in international negotiations. That's why our Recruiting and HR service makes collaborations as pleasurable as it possible. We appreciate honesty and trust accordingly we always provide our customers best solutions.

#### CEO & Founder at KitRUM LLC

June 2014 - Present (2 years 9 months)

KitRUM has found the best software development teams and connect them with growing companies that need world class teams and save time and money. We've developed a rigorous certification process that helps our clients find and engage the most talented development teams around the world.

#### Co-Founder at Source IT Ukraine

June 2013 - Present (3 years 9 months)

### Business trainer / Psychologist at Training Center "Brain"

April 2010 - December 2013 (3 years 9 months)

- Psychological consulting and coaching.
- Training course "Psychology (basic)".
- Training course "Psychologist-consultant".

- Training course "Lie theory".
- Training course "IT recruitment".

### Recruitment and HR consultant, coach at Sigma Ukraine

November 2010 - June 2013 (2 years 8 months)

- Trainings for IT leads, managers and mentors.
- Communication with customers.
- Organization of recruitment and HR processes for clients.
- Recruitment coordination of dedicated teams.
- "Hard-to-hire" staffing.
- HR consulting.

#### Recruiter / HR consultant at CreamTec

May 2010 - May 2013 (3 years 1 month)

- Recruitment and adaptation.
- Development and description of all HR processes from scratch.
- Consulting in HR management, team-building.
- Market analytical activities.
- Communication with customer.

### Entrepreneur at Freelance

May 2009 - November 2010 (1 year 7 months)

- IT-recruitment.
- sales, marketing, project-management, team-management.
- psychological and business trainings, development of own psychological studying programs.
- marketing researches, SEO, copyrighting, usability analytic of web-projects.

#### Deputy head of psychological department at Privat Bank

August 2006 - April 2009 (2 years 9 months)

- Psychological analysis, top-management consultations.
- Coordination and development of department business processes.
- Creation the automated psychological polls and automated system of psychological testing.
- Recruiting and leading team (60 specialists).
- Communication with internal and external customers.
- Management of few projects.

## Languages

### **English**

# Skills & Expertise

Hiring

**Sourcing** 

**Technical Recruiting** 

**Contract Negotiation** 

Negotiation

**Screening** 

**Requirements Analysis** 

**Customer Relations** 

**Interviewing** 

**Employee Relations** 

**Training & Development** 

**Coaching** 

**Executive Search** 

**Headhunting** 

**Management Consulting** 

Consultation

**Customer Service** 

### Education

### Kharkov National University of internal affairs

Specialist, Degree in psychology, 2001 - 2006

### Computer academy "Step"

Expert in computer graphics and Internet technologies, Web/Multimedia Management and

Webmaster, 2003 - 2005

### Kharkov Humanitarian Institute "People Ukrainian Academy".

Degree in economics and management, Marketing/Marketing Management, General, 2005 - 2008

# Tatyana Murashchenko

Entrepreneur, HR consultant, Soft-skills coach

tatyana.murashchenko@gmail.com



# 7 people have recommended Tatyana

— Yaroslav Kutukov, was with another company when working with Tatyana at Training Center "Brain"

"Tatyana is a positive, professional and knowledgeable recruiter I had the pleasure of working with. Tatyana quickly understand who we needed for the team from both a professional and team culture perspective. She also did her due diligence to understand how best to attract the right talent and how to source them. I have no hesitation recommending Tatyana's work."

— **Elena Alekseeva**, worked directly with Tatyana at Sigma Ukraine

"I worked a couple of years with Tatyana and I should say that she is outstanding both as a recruiter and HR manager. Tatyana is also proficient in organyzing psychological events and workshops. She is a workaholic and very reliable and polite person. Everyone will enjoy working together with Tatyana."

### — **Roman Oblogin**, worked directly with Tatyana at Sigma Ukraine

"I had a pleasure to work with Tatyana for several years. And I was particularly impressed by Tatyana's HR-manager ability to handle even the toughest situations inside the team and with the clients — and she did everything effortlessly. She can easily feel people and foresee their behavior and actions. That skill often takes years to develop among HR-managers, but it seemed to come perfectly naturally to her. I think her professionalism and experience give her ability to find solutions in situations where other people can just give up. With no doubt, she loves her work and completely dedicates herself to it. Any employee would be lucky to have Tatyana in his team."

— Michael Bondarenko, Application Engineer, AgileEngine, worked directly with Tatyana at CreamTec

"Tatyana is a very talented recruiting professional and has worked tirelessly to fill very difficult positions. She always finds great candidates in a short period of time. Tatyana always do a great job! She not only understands her job, but understands the nuances of both the job and the people with whom she must fit talent. I would highly recommend her to any company looking for one of the best recruitment professional!"

— Alexey Grebennikov, .NET Technical Lead, CreamTec LLC, worked directly with Tatyana at CreamTec

"Tatyana is an outstanding recruiting professional. She has a thorough grasp of the needs of today's fast-moving business environment, excellent contacts, and a can do great attitude. She is personable, intelligent, hard working and would be a great consultant for any corporate team."

— Vlad Kitaynik, VP of Solutions, AgileEngine, worked with Tatyana at CreamTec

"Tanya was the inspiration for the team. Well-organized, flexible and goal-oriented - her absence will be missed a lot. She has excellent communication skills which are the must in her professional field. It was a great pleasure to work with Tanya on lots of different projects."

— **Natalya Potapova**, worked directly with Tatyana at CreamTec

Contact Tatyana on LinkedIn